<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>GitHub on Giulio Vian's Blog!</title><link>http://blog.casavian.eu/tags/github/</link><description>Recent content in GitHub on Giulio Vian's Blog!</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2020 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://blog.casavian.eu/tags/github/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Blog updated: Hugo &amp; GitHub Actions</title><link>http://blog.casavian.eu/2020/04/25/blog-updated-hugo-github-actions/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2020 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.casavian.eu/2020/04/25/blog-updated-hugo-github-actions/</guid><description>I wrote a while ago about Automating Hugo to publish a blog. In that post, I used Azure Pipelines (well, they had a different name at that time).
Today, after three years, I revised the solution and I am amazed by Hugo &amp;nbsp; progress. Many of my customisations and hacks I implemented are gone: Hugo batteries included philosophy is a true thing.
In addition to using the most recent version &amp;ndash; 0.</description></item><item><title>Using GitVersion in GitHub Actions beta</title><link>http://blog.casavian.eu/2019/09/23/using-gitversion-in-github-actions-beta/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.casavian.eu/2019/09/23/using-gitversion-in-github-actions-beta/</guid><description>I was lucky to enter the GitHub Actions beta program so I wondered about the best way to test it. Finally, I decided to port Aggregator CLI &amp;nbsp; build scripts to GitHub Actions.
A critical step of those scripts is to run GitVersion &amp;nbsp; to generate the version for Aggregator. GitVersion, in the words of its authors, &amp;ldquo;looks at your git history and works out the semantic version of the commit being built.</description></item><item><title>Automate publishing documentation using Hugo and GitHub pages</title><link>http://blog.casavian.eu/2017/03/07/automate-publishing-documentation-using-hugo-and-github-pages/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.casavian.eu/2017/03/07/automate-publishing-documentation-using-hugo-and-github-pages/</guid><description>Many of you knows my work on TFS Aggregator &amp;nbsp; . Since the beginning we opted for Markdown &amp;nbsp; as the format for the project documentation, at the beginning they were some files in a doc folder, then I moved the content to the project&amp;rsquo;s GitHub Wiki, today I use the same files to generate the GitHub pages at https://tfsaggregator.github.io/intro/.
In this post I will describe how this latter step works in detail to publish our open source project&amp;rsquo;s documentation.</description></item></channel></rss>