<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Personal on Giulio Vian's Blog!</title><link>http://blog.casavian.eu/categories/personal/</link><description>Recent content in Personal on Giulio Vian's Blog!</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2014 19:53:35 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://blog.casavian.eu/categories/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My daughter is trying to convert me</title><link>http://blog.casavian.eu/2014/09/26/my-daughter-is-trying-to-convert-me/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2014 19:53:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.casavian.eu/2014/09/26/my-daughter-is-trying-to-convert-me/</guid><description>To classical music
and I was lucky: 40 euros per person and two hours drive.</description></item><item><title>My new job</title><link>http://blog.casavian.eu/2014/01/02/my-new-job/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.casavian.eu/2014/01/02/my-new-job/</guid><description>Fourteen year at Microsoft and less than two months for switching to a new company I knew nothing before. Even if my job constantly brought me here and there, becoming an expat will be hard.
The job is also challenging: this time I am on the Operations side, not on the Development team&amp;hellip; but an ALM platform like TFS is, by its nature, in between.
I will try to embody the DevOps principles, smoothing and easing the company&amp;rsquo;s workstream: my experience tells it&amp;rsquo;s a matter of automating, but how you do it is important as well.</description></item><item><title>New year!</title><link>http://blog.casavian.eu/2014/01/01/new-year-2014/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.casavian.eu/2014/01/01/new-year-2014/</guid><description>We have an old said “anno nuovo, vita nuova”, with the new year I have an important change in my life, so I have a new home for my blog. I quit Microsoft last year and I was pleasantly surprised by so many people reaching me. Some were amused by my goodbye email, and you, my dear reader, can also have fun.</description></item></channel></rss>