<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Personal on Giulio Vian's Blog!</title><link>http://blog.casavian.eu/tags/personal/</link><description>Recent content in Personal on Giulio Vian's Blog!</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2015 20:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://blog.casavian.eu/tags/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A new look for 2016 blog</title><link>http://blog.casavian.eu/2015/11/29/a-new-look-for-2016-blog/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2015 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.casavian.eu/2015/11/29/a-new-look-for-2016-blog/</guid><description>I did it again and changed my blog engine to Hugo &amp;nbsp; ; as a consequence you will find some small change in style and navigation.
The first and foremost reason is the complexity induced by Jekyll &amp;nbsp; . It requires some GB (who says that Visual Studio is big?) and many vodoo hacks to work on Windows. I ended having a Linux VM running Jekyll and some additional steps going from the Markdown file to a published post.</description></item><item><title>New look, but there is more</title><link>http://blog.casavian.eu/2014/10/18/new-blog-look/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.casavian.eu/2014/10/18/new-blog-look/</guid><description>What you see today is not a simple change in style, but a complete migration from WordPress to a static site.
The main driver for this decision is the disliked for LiveWriter or in-browser editor and conversely my growing reliance on Markdown. I tried using WordPress plugins for MD, like Mytory Markdown &amp;nbsp; , but the result was never satisfactory, as they do not support Github syntax.
So I moved from a basic AWS machine (see How I set-up this blog ), to a static web site on Azure.</description></item><item><title>My daughter is trying to convert me</title><link>http://blog.casavian.eu/2014/09/26/my-daughter-is-trying-to-convert-me/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2014 19:53:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.casavian.eu/2014/09/26/my-daughter-is-trying-to-convert-me/</guid><description>To classical music
and I was lucky: 40 euros per person and two hours drive.</description></item><item><title>How I set-up this blog</title><link>http://blog.casavian.eu/2014/01/03/how-i-set-up-this-blog/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.casavian.eu/2014/01/03/how-i-set-up-this-blog/</guid><description>It is amazing how easy is setting up your own environment, nowadays.
I am trying new Technologies now and, knowing Azure, I was curious about Amazon. Well, it is more or less the same amount of work: create an account, choose from the Marketplace a VM configured with a blog engine and, voilà, you&amp;rsquo;re ready to go. Some will turn up their nose on my choice of Wordpress, but I considered how easy is to create and move the content.</description></item><item><title>My new job</title><link>http://blog.casavian.eu/2014/01/02/my-new-job/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.casavian.eu/2014/01/02/my-new-job/</guid><description>Fourteen year at Microsoft and less than two months for switching to a new company I knew nothing before. Even if my job constantly brought me here and there, becoming an expat will be hard.
The job is also challenging: this time I am on the Operations side, not on the Development team&amp;hellip; but an ALM platform like TFS is, by its nature, in between.
I will try to embody the DevOps principles, smoothing and easing the company&amp;rsquo;s workstream: my experience tells it&amp;rsquo;s a matter of automating, but how you do it is important as well.</description></item><item><title>New year!</title><link>http://blog.casavian.eu/2014/01/01/new-year-2014/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.casavian.eu/2014/01/01/new-year-2014/</guid><description>We have an old said “anno nuovo, vita nuova”, with the new year I have an important change in my life, so I have a new home for my blog. I quit Microsoft last year and I was pleasantly surprised by so many people reaching me. Some were amused by my goodbye email, and you, my dear reader, can also have fun.</description></item></channel></rss>