<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blogging on Giulio Vian's Blog!</title><link>http://blog.casavian.eu/tags/blogging/</link><description>Recent content in Blogging on Giulio Vian's Blog!</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2020 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://blog.casavian.eu/tags/blogging/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Blog updated: Hugo &amp; GitHub Actions</title><link>http://blog.casavian.eu/2020/04/25/blog-updated-hugo-github-actions/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2020 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.casavian.eu/2020/04/25/blog-updated-hugo-github-actions/</guid><description>I wrote a while ago about Automating Hugo to publish a blog. In that post, I used Azure Pipelines (well, they had a different name at that time).
Today, after three years, I revised the solution and I am amazed by Hugo &amp;nbsp; progress. Many of my customisations and hacks I implemented are gone: Hugo batteries included philosophy is a true thing.
In addition to using the most recent version &amp;ndash; 0.</description></item><item><title>A new look for 2016 blog</title><link>http://blog.casavian.eu/2015/11/29/a-new-look-for-2016-blog/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2015 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.casavian.eu/2015/11/29/a-new-look-for-2016-blog/</guid><description>I did it again and changed my blog engine to Hugo &amp;nbsp; ; as a consequence you will find some small change in style and navigation.
The first and foremost reason is the complexity induced by Jekyll &amp;nbsp; . It requires some GB (who says that Visual Studio is big?) and many vodoo hacks to work on Windows. I ended having a Linux VM running Jekyll and some additional steps going from the Markdown file to a published post.</description></item><item><title>New look, but there is more</title><link>http://blog.casavian.eu/2014/10/18/new-blog-look/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.casavian.eu/2014/10/18/new-blog-look/</guid><description>What you see today is not a simple change in style, but a complete migration from WordPress to a static site.
The main driver for this decision is the disliked for LiveWriter or in-browser editor and conversely my growing reliance on Markdown. I tried using WordPress plugins for MD, like Mytory Markdown &amp;nbsp; , but the result was never satisfactory, as they do not support Github syntax.
So I moved from a basic AWS machine (see How I set-up this blog ), to a static web site on Azure.</description></item><item><title>How I set-up this blog</title><link>http://blog.casavian.eu/2014/01/03/how-i-set-up-this-blog/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://blog.casavian.eu/2014/01/03/how-i-set-up-this-blog/</guid><description>It is amazing how easy is setting up your own environment, nowadays.
I am trying new Technologies now and, knowing Azure, I was curious about Amazon. Well, it is more or less the same amount of work: create an account, choose from the Marketplace a VM configured with a blog engine and, voilà, you&amp;rsquo;re ready to go. Some will turn up their nose on my choice of Wordpress, but I considered how easy is to create and move the content.</description></item></channel></rss>